Carl Storms

Technology Evangelist | BIM Crusader | AECO Professional

With 25+ years of AECO experience, Carl excels in BIM and VDC, blending innovation with practicality. A curious learner of coding, automation, and AI-driven solutions, he explores cutting-edge technologies and shares insights through blogging, speaking. Always eager to discuss the latest industry workflows and trends.

1 403 554 0564

Ш

 \bowtie

Calgary, AB, Canada

•

bio.link/thebimsider

linkedin.com/in/cstorms in

github.com/TheBIMsider



WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Success Manager

Newforma

01/2020 - Present

- Driving product adoption and customer success through advocacy and education.
- Equipped sales teams with industry knowledge, product demos, and strategic insights, to improve conversion rates and streamline the sales process.
- Conducted in-depth analysis of current and emerging industry
 platforms, creating training materials and content to inform sales
 strategies and product positioning. Oversee special projects within
 the organization for emerging technologies.

Solutions Consultant

IMAGINIT Technologies

08/2012 - 01/2020

- Assess client's current business processes to recommend and implement solutions and application support for client BIM workflows
- Deliver application training to our clients, and industry-related technical presentations at seminars, workshops, conferences, user groups, both onsite and remotely. Customize training solutions where applicable
- Act as a brand ambassador seizing opportunities to increase IMAGINIT's visibility in the AEC marketplace

BIM Coordinator, IFP - Calgary International Airport

EllisDon Construction Services

05/2011 - 08/2012

- Led BIM/VDC coordination on projects, facilitating consultants, trades, and subcontractors through project phases.
- Managed 3D modeling processes for estimating, scheduling, logistics, and coordination, ensuring project-specific implementation.
- Provided project deployment support, including software setup, training, and 4D scheduling collaboration.

EDUCATION

Architectural Technician Diploma

Algonquin College

1995 – 1998

SKILLS

ACC/BIM360 | AI Prompts | APIs | AutoCAD
BIM | CSS | Dynamo | HTML | JavaScript | LLMs
MS Office | Navisworks | Power BI | Revit | VDC
Newforma Konekt | VS Code

SOFT SKILLS

Mentorship | Storytelling | Thought Leadership

SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS

165+ Presentations at Conferences, Trade Shows, User Groups, Webinars & More AU, BCS, BILT, bSNC, DBWa, DCW, HxGN, RTC & more 2013 - Present

 For over 10 years, I've had the privilege of speaking worldwide about BIM, VDC, AECO, and AI - from major conferences to local user groups, live or virtual. Along the way, I've been honored as a top speaker eight times. Full list here.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Speaker Mentor, SME

Autodesk University

2019, 2023 – Present

Caregiver, Foster & Fundraiser

Cats Home Foundation & CATF

08/2022 - Present

Industry Expert

CCA, AECO Task Force on BIM

03/2015 - 08/2018

INTERESTS

3D Printing | Al | Animals | Blogging | Low-Code Coding | Music | No-Code | Podcasting | Sports Making (Building & Tinkering) | Technology